

Sheikh Sayed Bin Rahman

Date of birth: 18/04/1996 | **Nationality:** Bangladeshi | **Phone number:**

(+880) 1521225714 (Mobile) | Email address: sayedrahman015@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sksayedrahman

Skype: https://join.skype.com/invite/rM6sCN6iD1ll

Address: House 152, Lane 6, Block T, Mirpur 12, Dhaka, 1216, Dhaka,

Bangladesh (Home)

ABOUT ME

As a researcher and software engineer, I'm energized by complex problems. I flourish in collaborative settings that require dedication and ownership. Ultimately, I find the most fulfillment in environments that value creative problem-solving and celebrate significant contributions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/09/2022 - CURRENT Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER TOGETHER INITIATIVES (P) LTD

- Developed and maintained automated test scripts using Cypress , Playwright and Javascript, Typescript.
- Performed manual and automated tests to ensure accuracy and integrity of software applications
- Worked as a backend engineer for Visitor Management System using Spring Boot , Spring Data , MS SQI , JPA and created restful Apis

Email sksayed@i2gether.com/ | Website https://www.i2gether.com/

01/10/2020 - 01/03/2022 Dhaka, Bangladesh

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER GO MAX AUTOMATION LIMITED

- Design flutter widgets and Development of a Vehicle Tracking mobile app using Flutter for both android and los
- Using Dart Language with Flutter Bloc as state management , shared preference , google maps , hive to build app
- Publishing apps to playstore and maintaing reslease versions
- Integrating restful Api's from Backend

01/10/2019 - 30/09/2020 Dhaka, Bangladesh

JUNIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER DAILY GOODS LIMITED

- Implemented Mobile UI using XML for rider app and delivery feature
- Build android app using MVVM pattern , LiveData , Java 8 , RxJava , Retrofit , Piccaso , Google Maps , Firebase , Okhttp
- Build User and Admin Dashboard using Vaadin and Java 8
- Integrated Restful Apis

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/01/2016 – 07/09/2019 Dhaka, Bangladesh

BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING American International University Bangladesh

Website https://www.aiub.edu | Final grade 3.74 out of 4.0 | Number of credits 148 |

Thesis An IoT Based Model of a Nitrogen Detection System for Soil Samples

HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE (H.S.C) Chattogram Cantonment Public College

Website https://ccpc.edu.bd | Field of study Science | Final grade 5.00

2012 Chottogram, Bangladesh

SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE (S.S.C) Chattogram Cantonment Public College

Website https://ccpc.edu.bd | Field of study Science | Final grade 5.00

PUBLICATIONS

2020

An IoT Based Model of a Nitrogen Detection System for Soil Samples

IoT plays an important role in smart irrigation system. Using new technology on agricultural field will be very much helpful in cultivation. This study provides a brief overview on the most important nutrient nitrogen (N) detection in soil. A portable device model proposed in this study that can be used to detect concentration of Nitrogen from a soil sample

Co Author: I. Ahmed, F. Ahmed. ICCA January 2020; Article No.: 59: Pages 1-5.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

05/2018 - 08/2019

Undergrad Thesis Project: An IoT Based Model of a Nitrogen Detection System for Soil Samples

- Background studies includes existing exisiting Nitrogen detection methods and tools , systematic literature review of scholary articles , researches in this domain.
- Designed and implemented suggested low cost IOT model for use
- Designed detection algorithm using C++ and Java for Arduino Uno
- · Survayed and data collected through experiment in AIUB lab

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Java(SE), Dart, C#, PHP **Framework:** Spring Boot, Spring, Laravel, Asp.net Core

Mobile Development: Native & Cross Platform Android Development with Android Sdk and Flutter

Testing Tool: Cypress, Playwright

Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle 10g (PL/SQL), SQLite **Programming IDE:** Android Studio, Intelij Idea, Visual Studio, VS Code

Project Management Tools: Jira, Trello

Build Tool: Maven, Gradle

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Mac

Others: Git, Microsoft Word, Excel

PROJECTS

10/2022 - CURRENT

Visitor Management System

Worked as a developer as well as architect for backend of Visitor Management System . I have developed Restful Apis for the whole system including Authentication and Authorization.

Tools and technologies: Java, Spring Boot 2, JPA, Hibernate, Jasper report, MS SQL, Docker

2018

Point of sells desktop application developed by .NET

- Two types of user such as Employee and Admin
- Admin can manage inventory, Employee, Customer and Employees can manage customer only
- Employee will help in selling products and generate invoice report

Role: Developer, Database Administrator.

Technologies: Tools and Technologies: C#, win forms, Entity Framework as ORM, Metro UI, Crystal Reports for reporting, MS SQL server 12.

Link https://github.com/sksayed/Point-of-Sell

04/2019

Internet of Things in classrooms through discovery-based learning and physical computing

I tried to contribute in this project by systematic literature review as well as building projects with sensors and computing devices such as arduino uno..

2020

Dynamic street light control for smart cities use cases using IOT based monitoring system

I tried to enrich this project by engaging in a comprehensive systematic literature review, while also crafting innovative projects utilizing sensors and computing devices, such as the Arduino Uno and utilizing my coding skills to make an automatic monitoring system

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **BENGALI**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

VOLUNTEERING

01/05/2018 - 30/04/2019 Dhaka, Bangladesh

AIUB Computer Club

As a member of the esteemed Aiub Computer Club at the American International University-Bangladesh, I've contributed to organizing impactful events like CS Fest and Cyber Gaming Festival, and facilitated seminars. These experiences fostered a sense of patronage and ignited a passion for aiding others.

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

2020 Dhaka, Bangladesh

International Conference on Computing Advancements (ICCA) - 2020

Graced with the opportunity to showcase my scholarly contributions, I proudly attended the ICCA conference as an author, where my debut paper was published.

2023 Cox's Bazar

International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (ICCIT) - 2023

I had the privilege of attending ICCIT as an honored visitor, where I had the pleasure of engaging with esteemed scholars and authors. During these interactions, I had the opportunity to initiate discussions about potential collaborations in the captivating domain of Natural Language Processing (NLP)

2023 Dhaka

APQN Academic Conference (AAC) - 2023

I have perticipated in AAC as a visitor

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: A2 **Driving Licence:** B

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Travelling

Photography

RECOMMENDATIONS

MASHIOUR RAHMAN Dean-in-charge, Computer Science

I have studied a course called Theory of computation under his supervision directly , also i have been a sincere sutdent of his

Email mashiour@aiub.edu

MOHAIMEN BIN NOOR Assistant Professor & Special Assistant [CS], Computer Science

I have been under his direct supervision for the course Object Oriented Analysis and Design , Apart from that he knows me personally as an obedient student and honest personality.

Email mohaimen.niloy@aiub.edu